caravanclub.co.uk 2016-11-23

# Privacy Policy | The Caravan Club

### 1\. Information about us

The Caravan Club Limited, trading as The Caravan Club, is the owner and operator of www.caravanclub.co.uk (our **website** ) and any applications and/or digital channels provided by us for the purpose of accessing our website, digital magazine or other services (our **apps** and **digital channels** ) (together our **digital services** ). We are a company limited by guarantee registered in England and Wales under company number 646027. Our registered trading address is The Caravan Club, East Grinstead House, East Grinstead, West Sussex RH19 1UA. Our VAT number is 239719331.

### 2\. Contact us

If you would like any information about The Caravan Club and its activities you can contact us by telephone on 01342 326944 or email [enquiries@caravanclub.co.uk](mailto:enquiries@caravanclub.co.uk). You can also write to The Caravan Club at East Grinstead House, East Grinstead, West Sussex RH19 1UA. If you have any queries relating to these Terms of Use, our Privacy Policy or Use of Cookies policy, please contact the Data Security Compliance Manager by letter at our registered trading address above.

A comprehensive list of contact telephone numbers and email addresses can be found on our website at Contact & FAQs. Thank you for using our digital services.

### 3\. Privacy policy

### 3.1. Policy

The Caravan Club Limited ( **We** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our Terms of Use and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our policy and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting our digital services you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998, the data controller is The Caravan Club Limited and our Data Security Compliance Manager is our nominated person for data protection.

### 3.2. How do we collect information?

We obtain personal information from you when you enquire about our activities, register with us, become a member or renew membership, send or receive email, make a donation of memorabilia to us, purchase products, ask a question or otherwise provide us with personal information. We may also receive information about you from third parties, for example from our service providers or from a friend who wants to tell you about our digital services.

### 3.3. What information do we collect?

The personal information we collect will depend on the nature of the transaction. It might include name, date of birth, email address, postal address, telephone number and bank account details. Although we may take credit/debit card information to complete a transaction, we do not store this information.

Certain personal information is categorised by the Data Protection Act 1998 as ‘sensitive personal data’. In some circumstances, we provide you with the opportunity to inform us of your sensitive personal data, e.g. whether or not you are registered as disabled. You may also wish to inform us about your sensitive personal data to ensure that we can provide you with the most appropriate service. By providing us with this data you are consenting to our processing it for the purposes for which it was given, e.g. the allocation of an appropriate pitch at the National Rally. Please note that if you fail to inform us of any sensitive personal data which may be relevant to your circumstances, this may mean that we cannot provide you with the most appropriate service.

We also gather general information about the use of our digital services, such as which pages users visit most often and which services, events or facilities are of most interest. We may also track which pages users visit when they click on links in emails. We may use this information to personalise the way our digital services are presented when users visit them, to make improvements to our digital services and to ensure we provide the best service for users. Wherever possible we use aggregated or anonymous information which does not identify individual visitors to our digital services. For more information on this, please see our Use of Cookies policy.

### 3.4. Cookies

Our digital services use cookies to distinguish you from other users of our digital services. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our digital services and also allows us to improve our digital services. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our Use of Cookies policy.

### 3.5. How do we use this information?

Depending on your relationship with us, we will use your personal information for the following purposes: 

a) to provide you with the services, products or information you have requested  
b) to administer your membership and/or account  
c) to provide information to you about us and the membership benefits provided by us and third parties  
d) to enable you to transact within certain areas of our digital services and perform activities such as make site bookings or complete enquiry forms   
e) for general administration purposes, such as handling your enquiries and managing purchases of products and services  
f) to carry out research  
g) to guide and support the general objectives of The Caravan Club  
h) statutory and regulatory compliance  
i) to further our charitable activities, including fundraising

As part of this, we may analyse the personal information we collect to create a profile of your interests and preferences so that we can contact you in the most appropriate way and with the most relevant information. Where relevant, we may also assess your personal information for the purposes of fraud and credit risk reduction.

If you enter your contact details in one of our online registration forms, we may use this information to contact you even if you do not "send" or "submit" the form. We will only do this to see if we can help with any problems you might be experiencing with the form or with our digital services.

We may need to share your information with our service providers, associated organisations and agents for the purposes described above but we never sell your information to other organisations.

### 3.6. Your choices

You have a choice about whether you want to receive information about our services. We will not use your personal information for marketing purposes or share your information with any third party if you have indicated that you do not wish to be contacted in this manner.

You can change your marketing preferences at any time by:

  * writing to Membership Services at our registered address provided in Section 1 or calling us on 01342 318813, or
  * if you are a member, you can also update your preferences online using the “My Profile” section of the website

Please note that if you do request not to receive marketing information, you will continue to receive communications relating to the administration of your membership or account and any services purchased.

Our digital services may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites or apps of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites or apps, please note that they have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### 3.7. How do we protect your personal information?

All of our online forms that may collect personal data are protected by encryption and we also use secure third party payments services when you make a payment via our digital services. We take appropriate measures to safeguard personal information that is disclosed to us and keep it secure, accurate and up to date.

### 3.8. Will we disclose the information we collect to outside parties?

As indicated above, we may pass your information to our service providers, agents and associated organisations for the purpose of completing tasks and providing services to you.

We may also need to disclose your information if required by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies) or if we have your permission to do so.

We will not sell any information about your web browsing activity.

### 3.9. Your consent

By providing us with your personal data, including any sensitive personal data, you consent to the collection and use of this information in accordance with the purposes described above and this privacy policy.

You consent to us using your information to send you communications by electronic means, including by SMS, email and telephone. You also consent to our transferring your information to countries or jurisdictions outside the European Economic Area if necessary for the above purposes. These countries may not provide the same level of data protection as the UK and if we do make such a transfer, we will put appropriate controls in place so that your information is protected.

### 3.10. Right of access

If you have registered with us on our website, you can sign into your account to access and update your information. You also have the right to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a small fee) – this is known as a Subject Access Request. A Subject Access Request form has been developed to make the request process easy for you and to ensure that we have all the information we need to be able to process your request. The form can be downloaded here. Please complete all relevant information and post to the Data Security Compliance Manager at our registered address, as set out in the form.

You do not have to use the form to make a request but we will need all the information asked for on the form in order to process your request. You may also request to have any inaccuracies in your information corrected by writing to us.

### 3.11. Changes

If your personal details change, please help us to keep your information up to date by notifying us at: Membership Services, The Caravan Club, East Grinstead House, East Grinstead, West Sussex RH19 1UA. If you are a member, you can change some information held about you by accessing your profile online.

We may change the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time. By continuing to use our digital services any changes will be deemed to have been accepted by you.

Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our Privacy Policy.

**Version No.** | **Description of Change** | **Date Published**  
---|---|---  
2.0 | Major update to original policy | 25 November 2015  
2.1 | Section 1 updated to include "digital channels" and  
clarify the meaning of digital services. | 21 January 2016  
  
### 3.12. Monitoring of telephone calls

Your telephone calls to us may be recorded and monitored for quality control purposes.

### 3.13. Last update

This Privacy Policy (Version 2.1) was last updated on 21 January 2016.
